pimco.com 2019-04-20

# Privacy Policy | PIMCO

**Privacy Policies**

**Last revised: February 2017**

**Pacific Investment Management Company LLC (“PIMCO”)**

PIMCO considers customer privacy to be a fundamental aspect of its relationship with clients. PIMCO is committed to maintaining the confidentiality, integrity, and security of its current, prospective and former clients' non-public personal information. PIMCO has developed policies that are designed to protect this confidentiality, while allowing client needs to be served. 

In the course of providing its clients with products and services, PIMCO and certain of its service providers may obtain non-public personal information about its clients. This information may come from sources such as account applications and other forms, from other written, electronic or verbal correspondence, from client transactions, from client brokerage or financial advisory firm, financial adviser or consultant, and/or from information captured on applicable websites.

As a matter of policy, PIMCO does not disclose any non-public personal information provided by its clients or gathered by PIMCO to non-affiliated third parties, except as required or permitted by law or for PIMCO's everyday business purposes, such as to process transactions or service a client account. As is common in the industry, non-affiliated companies may from time to time be used to provide certain services, such as preparing and mailing prospectuses, reports, account statements and other information, conducting research on client satisfaction, and gathering shareholder proxies. PIMCO (or its affiliates) may also retain non-affiliated companies to market its products, and may enter into joint marketing arrangements with them and other companies. These companies may have access to client personal and account information, but are permitted to use the information solely to provide the specific service or as otherwise permitted by law. PIMCO may also provide client personal and account information to their brokerage or financial advisory firm and/or to their financial adviser or consultant.

PIMCO reserves the right to disclose or report personal or account information to non-affiliated third parties in limited circumstances where PIMCO believes in good faith that disclosure is required under law, to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement authorities, to protect its rights or property, or upon reasonable request by any of its mutual funds in which clients have invested. In addition, PIMCO may disclose information about a client or their accounts to a non-affiliated third party at their request or if the client consents in writing to the disclosure. 

PIMCO may share client information with its affiliates in connection with servicing a client account, and subject to applicable law may provide a client with information about products and services that PIMCO or its affiliates believe may be of interest to the client. The information that PIMCO may share may include, for example, information about PIMCO’s or its mutual funds' experiences and transactions with a client, their participation in its mutual funds or other investment programs, their ownership of certain types of accounts (such as IRAs), information captured on applicable websites, or other data about their accounts, subject to applicable law. PIMCO’s affiliates, in turn, are not permitted to share client information with non-affiliated entities, except as required or permitted by law. 

PIMCO takes seriously the obligation to safeguard a client’s non-public personal information. In addition to this policy, PIMCO has implemented procedures that are designed to restrict access to a client’s non-public personal information to its personnel who need to know that information to perform their jobs, such as servicing a client’s account or notifying a client of new products and services. Physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards are in place to guard a client’s non-public personal information.

Websites maintained by PIMCO or its service providers may use a variety of technologies to collect information that help PIMCO and its service providers understand how the website is used. Information collected from a client’s web browser (including small files stored on a client’s device that are commonly referred to as “cookies”) allow the websites to recognize a client’s web browser and help to personalize and improve a client’s user experience and enhance navigation of the website. In addition, PIMCO or certain of its service providers may use third parties to place advertisements for PIMCO products on other websites, including banner advertisements. Such third parties may collect anonymous information through the use of cookies or action tags (such as web beacons). The information these third parties collect is generally limited to technical and web navigation information, such as a client’s IP address, web pages visited and browser type, and does not include personally identifiable information such as name, address, phone number or email address. If a client is a registered user of PIMCO’s website, PIMCO or its service providers or third party firms engaged by PIMCO or its service providers may collect or share the information a client submits to us, which may include personally identifiable information. This information can be useful to PIMCO when assessing and offering services and website features for a client. A client can change their cookie preferences by changing the setting on their web browser to delete or reject cookies. If a client deletes or rejects cookies, some website pages may not function properly. PIMCO does not look for web browser "do not track" requests.

From time to time, PIMCO may update or revise this privacy policy. If there are changes to the terms of this privacy policy, documents containing the revised policy on the relevant website will be updated.

**PIMCO Funds  
PIMCO Variable Insurance Trust (“PVIT”)   
PIMCO ETF Trust  
PIMCO Equity Series (“PES”)   
PIMCO Equity Series VIT (“PESVIT”)   
PIMCO Managed Accounts Trust  
PIMCO Sponsored Closed-End Funds   
PIMCO Sponsored Interval Funds1  
PIMCO Investments LLC2**

The Funds consider customer privacy to be a fundamental aspect of their relationships with shareholders and are committed to maintaining the confidentiality, integrity and security of their current, prospective and former shareholders’ non-public personal information. The Funds have developed policies that are designed to protect this confidentiality, while allowing shareholder needs to be served. 

**Obtaining Personal Information**

In the course of providing shareholders with products and services, the Funds and certain service providers to the Funds, such as the Funds’ investment advisers or sub-advisers (“Advisers”), may obtain non-public personal information about shareholders, which may come from sources such as account applications and other forms, from other written, electronic or verbal correspondence, from shareholder transactions, from a shareholder’s brokerage or financial advisory firm, financial advisor or consultant, and/or from information captured on applicable websites. 

**Respecting Your Privacy**

As a matter of policy, the Funds do not disclose any non-public personal information provided by shareholders or gathered by the Funds to non-affiliated third parties, except as required or permitted by law or as necessary for such third parties to perform their agreements with respect to the Funds. As is common in the industry, non-affiliated companies may from time to time be used to provide certain services, such as preparing and mailing prospectuses, reports, account statements and other information, conducting research on shareholder satisfaction and gathering shareholder proxies. The Funds or their affiliates may also retain non-affiliated companies to market Fund shares or products which use Fund shares and enter into joint marketing arrangements with them and other companies. These companies may have access to a shareholder’s personal and account information, but are permitted to use this information solely to provide the specific service or as otherwise permitted by law. In most cases, the shareholders will be clients of a third party, but the Funds may also provide a shareholder’s personal and account information to the shareholder’s respective brokerage or financial advisory firm and/or financial advisor or consultant. 

**Sharing Information with Third Parties**

The Funds reserve the right to disclose or report personal or account information to non-affiliated third parties in limited circumstances where the Funds believe in good faith that disclosure is required under law, to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement authorities, to protect their rights or property, or upon reasonable request by any Fund in which a shareholder has invested. In addition, the Funds may disclose information about a shareholder or a shareholder’s accounts to a non-affiliated third party at the shareholder’s request or with the consent of the shareholder. 

**Sharing Information with Affiliates**

The Funds may share shareholder information with their affiliates in connection with servicing shareholders’ accounts, and subject to applicable law may provide shareholders with information about products and services that the Funds or their Advisers, distributors or their affiliates (“Service Affiliates”) believe may be of interest to such shareholders. The information that the Funds may share may include, for example, a shareholder’s participation in the Funds or in other investment programs sponsored by a Service Affiliate, a shareholder’s ownership of certain types of accounts (such as IRAs), information about the Funds’ experiences or transactions with a shareholder, information captured on applicable websites, or other data about a shareholder’s accounts, subject to applicable law. The Funds’ Service Affiliates, in turn, are not permitted to share shareholder information with non-affiliated entities, except as required or permitted by law. 

**Procedures to Safeguard Private Information**

The Funds take seriously the obligation to safeguard shareholder non-public personal information. In addition to this policy, the Funds have implemented procedures that are designed to restrict access to a shareholder’s non-public personal information to internal personnel who need to know that information to perform their jobs, such as servicing shareholder accounts or notifying shareholders of new products or services. Physical, electronic and procedural safeguards are in place to guard a shareholder’s non-public personal information. 

**Information Collected from Websites**

Websites maintained by the Funds or their service providers may use a variety of technologies to collect information that help the Funds and their service providers understand how the website is used. Information collected from your web browser (including small files stored on your device that are commonly referred to as “cookies”) allow the websites to recognize your web browser and help to personalize and improve your user experience and enhance navigation of the website. In addition, the Funds or their Service Affiliates may use third parties to place advertisements for the Funds on other websites, including banner advertisements. Such third parties may collect anonymous information through the use of cookies or action tags (such as web beacons). The information these third parties collect is generally limited to technical and web navigation information, such as your IP address, web pages visited and browser type, and does not include personally identifiable information such as name, address, phone number or email address. If you are a registered user of the Funds’ website, the Funds or their service providers or third party firms engaged by the Funds or their service providers may collect or share information submitted by you, which may include personally identifiable information. This information can be useful to the Funds when assessing and offering services and website features. You can change your cookie preferences by changing the setting on your web browser to delete or reject cookies. If you delete or reject cookies, some website pages may not function properly. The Funds do not look for web browser “do not track” requests. 

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

From time to time, the Funds may update or revise this privacy policy. If there are changes to the terms of this privacy policy, documents containing the revised policy on the relevant website will be updated.

* * *

1 PIMCO Funds, PVIT, PIMCO ETF Trust, PES, PESVIT and PIMCO Managed Accounts Trust are referred to collectively as the “Trusts.” The listed entities which are publicly-traded closed-end investment companies are known as the “Closed-End Funds,” and the listed entities which are closed-end investment companies operating as “interval” funds under Rule 23c-3 under the 1940 Act are known as the “Interval Funds.” The Trusts, the Closed-End Funds and the Interval Funds are referred to collectively as the “Funds.”

2 PIMCO Investments LLC (“PI”) serves as the Trusts’ distributor. This Privacy Policy applies to the activities of PI to the extent that PI regularly effects or engages in transactions with or for a shareholder of a series of a Trust who is the record owner of such shares. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, references to “the Funds” shall include PI when acting in this capacity.
